<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Akshit Arora</title>
    <description>Artificial Intelligence, Deep Learning and Photography</description>
    <link>http://localhost:4000/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <pubDate>Tue, 13 Mar 2018 02:54:15 -0600</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 13 Mar 2018 02:54:15 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.7.2</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Building Chatbot Prototypes</title>
        <description>&lt;h2 id=&quot;chatbots&quot;&gt;Chatbots!&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The great wall between you and the customer care representative who can easily resolve your issue. I don’t think I need to repeat the good and the bad of chatbots, it’s pretty much all over the internet:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.forbes.com/sites/blakemorgan/2017/03/09/what-is-a-chatbot-and-why-is-it-important-for-customer-experience/#1378c2471886&quot;&gt;What Is A Chatbot, And Why Is It Important For Customer Experience? - Forbes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://chatbotsmagazine.com/why-its-important-for-a-business-to-have-a-chatbot-28e446ce7167&quot;&gt;Why It’s Important For a Business To Have a Chatbot - ChatBotsMagazine&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://chatbotsmagazine.com/top-5-benefits-with-using-chatbots-for-your-business-159a0cee7d8a&quot;&gt;Top 5 Benefits Of Using Chatbots For Your Business - ChatBotsMagazine&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://venturebeat.com/2017/06/19/how-chatbots-are-good-for-business/&quot;&gt;How chatbots are good for business? - VentureBeat&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;so-why-am-i-interested-in-it&quot;&gt;So, Why am I interested in it?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The property of chatbots that separates them from other mediums of interaction with technology is their capacity to understand and respond in natural language. And this very characteristic fascinates me. If someday, using some technology, we are able to give chatbots ‘general intelligence’, they might as well be used (besides all the applications we use them for, today):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;For treating people suffering from depression - Sometimes it becomes very difficult to fully express yourself to another human being due to several reasons. Can be used to help military personnel sent off to difficult missions / astronauts / etc. People have begun exploring this use-case: &lt;a href=&quot;https://woebot.io/&quot;&gt;Woebot&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;As a virtual friend - Who is available 24*7 to talk to you and learns more about you over time.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;To help you organize your thoughts - By maintaining journals and giving you the ability to monitor your thought process over time. Therefore giving you a self feedback tool.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;To help you learn a new concept (Personalized learning) - If the chatbot has learnt so much about you, it will be able to teach any new concept to you in a way you can understand. And I am not just talking about language here, every person has a distinct learning process that usually stays consistent over time (its just my personal experience though), this can be exploited to make better chatbots.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Mimic someone’s voice - We already have the tech (&lt;a href=&quot;https://deepmind.com/blog/wavenet-generative-model-raw-audio/&quot;&gt;WaveNet&lt;/a&gt;) for this though. This one is just for fun!&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Providing Motivation - Helps keep up your motivation and lets you see the bigger picture at all times. Adding facial recognition to it will also help for this use-case.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Productivity Tracker - Captures your activity (online and offline) and calculates your productivity for the day. (Thanks IoT!)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Wait, doesn’t all of this sound like &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.imdb.com/title/tt1798709/&quot;&gt;Her&lt;/a&gt;? or &lt;a href=&quot;http://marvel-movies.wikia.com/wiki/J.A.R.V.I.S.&quot;&gt;J.A.R.V.I.S.&lt;/a&gt;? Well, it does (but only some use-cases, not all), human beings are biased =&amp;gt; so am I :P&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All of the use cases mentioned above have their ethical issues associated with them. But we can all agree, they do sound like something one can use on a daily basis. Such potential applications make me curious as to how lives will change when people start using such tools?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-is-this-post-about&quot;&gt;What is this post about?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I started out with chatbots (during my undergrad), with my limited knowledge and exposure, I tried to deploy, the then popular, &lt;a href=&quot;https://jasperproject.github.io/&quot;&gt;Jasper - an open source platform for developing voice-controlled applications&lt;/a&gt;. For months, I tried to emulate a Raspberry Pi on my linux machine to run this software. Ultimately I had to give up!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But, in recent years there have been many developments in the open source community and industry around personal assistants. We all know about Cortana, Siri, Google Assistant and Alexa. But, there have been several open source competitors as well such as:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://mycroft.ai/&quot;&gt;Mycroft&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.lucida.ai/&quot;&gt;Lucida&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.theadrianproject.com/&quot;&gt;Adrian&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can hack around these projects as much as you like. But this post is about ideas surrounding chatbots and not the ways to actually build it. In this post I will be discussing about 4 online tools to build prototypes of voice/text user interfaces, a.k.a., Chatbots:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://chatfuel.com/&quot;&gt;Chatfuel&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reply.ai/&quot;&gt;Reply.ai&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://wit.ai/&quot;&gt;Wit.ai&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://dialogflow.com/&quot;&gt;Dialogflow&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;to-be-continued&quot;&gt;To Be Continued…&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;acknowledgements&quot;&gt;Acknowledgements:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I thank &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/realjoet&quot;&gt;Joe Toscano&lt;/a&gt; for his guidance on the tools to build prototypes for voice user interfaces. I wish him good luck! for his upcoming book &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.designingintelligence.com/&quot;&gt;Designing Intelligence&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;additional-resources&quot;&gt;Additional Resources:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://chatbotsmagazine.com/&quot;&gt;Chatbots Magazine&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://botlist.co/&quot;&gt;Botlist&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.muz.li/the-ultimate-guide-to-chatbots-why-theyre-disrupting-ux-and-best-practices-for-building-345e2150b682&quot;&gt;The Ultimate Guide to Chatbots: Why they’re disrupting UX and best practices for building - Joe Toscano&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/@SysCoder/chatbot-presentations-2f28e3c3be81&quot;&gt;Chatbot Presentations - Marcellus Pelcher&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=QkX2U5Dhf-A&quot;&gt;Tic Tac Toe with Google Home - Marcellus Pelcher&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 12 Mar 2018 07:25:18 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/artificialintelligence/2018/03/12/chatbots/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/artificialintelligence/2018/03/12/chatbots/</guid>
        
        <category>chatbots</category>
        
        <category>conversational modelling</category>
        
        <category>UI/UX design</category>
        
        
        <category>ArtificialIntelligence</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Neural Conversational Model</title>
        <description>&lt;h2 id=&quot;summary&quot;&gt;Summary&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The paper talks about an end-to-end framework based on using neural networks for mapping input sequences (statements) to output sequences (responses). This approach differs from conventional conversational systems because it lacks domain knowledge, can be trained end-to-end and requires fewer hand-crafted rules. The model predicts the next sentence given the previous sentence / sentences in a conversation. 
&lt;img src=&quot;/img/1.PNG&quot; alt=&quot;seq2seq model&quot; /&gt;
A sequence to sequence, called &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/abs/1409.3215&quot;&gt;seq2seq&lt;/a&gt; framework which takes input of one token at one timestamp and outputs one token at one timestamp. The framework is established using RNNs. The training phase involves learning the given true output through back propagation. In language tasks the objective is to decrease the perplexity and in this task as well the model is trained to maximize the cross entropy of the correct sequence using the context.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;datasets-used&quot;&gt;Datasets Used&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;IT Helpdesk Troubleshooting Dataset (Training set: 30M tokens, validation set: 3M tokens)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;OpenSubtitles Dataset (Tiedermann, 2009). (Training set: 923M tokens, validation set: 395M tokens)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;advantages&quot;&gt;Advantages:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Since we are using neural networks, it is easy to use the same model for machine translation, question/answering and conversations without major changes in architecture.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Can generate simple and basic conversations using very few hand-crafted rules unlike conventional bots.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Able to extract knowledge from domain specific dataset (IT Helpdesk, finding solution to a technical problem) and from a large, noisy and general domain dataset of movie subtitles (common sense reasoning).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;disadvantages&quot;&gt;Disadvantages:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Unlike easier tasks like Translation, this model does not completely solve the problem of modelling dialogue because:&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The objective function being optimized does not capture the actual objective of human communication.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Since it is a purely unsupervised model, it is unable to ensure consistency and general world knowledge.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Lack of personality. Hence cannot pass the Turing test. A paper by Microsoft talks about this limitation and introduces persona-based neural conversational models. (Find it &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/abs/1603.06155&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;No performance measure to calculate quality of models except manual inspection and perplexity.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;related-works&quot;&gt;Related Works:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://neuralconvo.huggingface.co/&quot;&gt;NeuralConvo&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://sidgan.me/technical/2016/05/24/the_neural_conversation_model&quot;&gt;The Neural Conversational Model by Siddha Ganju&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 09 Nov 2017 06:25:18 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/artificialintelligence/2017/11/09/neural-conversational-model/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/artificialintelligence/2017/11/09/neural-conversational-model/</guid>
        
        <category>ai</category>
        
        <category>ml</category>
        
        <category>nlp</category>
        
        <category>brain</category>
        
        <category>deep learning</category>
        
        <category>conversational modelling</category>
        
        
        <category>ArtificialIntelligence</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
